聖費爾南多谷 洛杉磯16英里以北
# ...你的眼神 #
...look in your eye
# 而我有著紅唇和那些優雅 都是你所愛的 #
And I got that red lip classic thing that you like
# 每當我們橫衝直撞 卻總能和好如初 #
And when we go crashing down, we come back every time
# 因為我們永遠如經典般存在 #
'Cause we never go out of style
# 我們永不過時 #
We never go out of style
# 你留著長髮 梳著大背頭 穿著白色T恤 #
You got that long hair, slicked back, white t-shirt
# 而我有著好女孩的樣子 穿著緊身裙 #
And I got that good girl faith and a tight little skirt
# 每當我們橫衝直撞 卻總能和好如初 #
And when we go crashing down, we come back every time
真是笑死我了 妹子.. 你和喬什是怎麼回事
# 因為我們永遠如經典般存在 #
'Cause we never go out of style
# 我們永不過時 #
We never go out of style
啊
Aah!
救命
Help!
我知道你們都隸屬於駐紮在阿富汗巴格拉姆
So, uh, I understand that you all were part
軍事基地的五十八號救援分隊
of the fifty-eighth rescue squadron staged over at bagram
執行空中巡邏營救任務
in Afghanistan for combat search and rescue.
是的 女士 去過兩次
Yes, ma'am. Two tours.
你們現在仍然是搭檔嗎
And you're still flying together?
是的 我們感情都挺好的 像一家人一樣
Yeah, we all got pretty tight over there. Wouldn't break up the family.
兄弟 我們像是一家的嗎
Dude, do we look like family?
一點點吧
A little.
那麼 在阿富汗時的救援
So, what's the biggest difference
和在這堛漱u作有什麼不同嗎
between rescuing over there and what you do here?
這堣ㄦ|吃槍子兒
Not getting shot at.
你真是個有趣的傢伙
You're a funny guy.
是吧 一般般啦
Yeah. Not exactly.
呃 蓋恩斯首長
Um... chief Gaines?
據我所知在阿富汗和洛杉磯消防局任期間
I'm told that between Afghanistan and LAFD,
你拯救了超過六百餘人的生命
you have over six hundred documented rescues.
這真讓人印象深刻
That's, uh...pretty impressive.
本職工作而已 女士
Just doin' my job, ma'am.
絕對服從命令
Go where they tell me to go.
很不錯 你可以停止拍攝了
That's great. You can cut there.
她在那
There she is.
峽谷太窄了
Looks pretty tight.
把她拉上來
Take her up.
風向不斷在變化
Winds are variable.
在270度到300度間搖擺
Two-seven-zero to three-zero-zero.
風速由十節上升為十五節
Ten knots gusting to fifteen.
呼叫總部 洛杉磯消防隊
Metro, this is LAFD.
五號直升機已到達事故現場
Helo five on scene of cliff-v rescue.
我們看到了受困者
We have visual.
- 收到 直升機五號 - 那女孩叫什麼
- Copy, Helo five. - What's the girl's name?
納塔莉
Natalie.
總部 把她的手機轉到我們這
Metro, connect her cell to our sat phone.
直升機五號 你們已經連上了
Helo five, you're connected.
你好
Hello?
納塔莉 我是機長雷蒙德蓋恩斯
Natalie, this is chief pilot Raymond Gaines
來自洛杉磯消防局
of the Los Angeles fire department.
我正開著直升機在你上方
I'm piloting the chopper above you.
你還好嗎
You holdin' up all right?
我不知道 感覺不太好
I don't know. I'm not feeling very well.
天哪 車子正在下滑
Oh, my God! The car is sliding.
納塔莉 我需要你保持冷靜 親愛的
Natalie, I'm gonna need you to stay calm, honey.
- 我們現在來救你 好嗎 - 好吧
- We're coming to get you, okay? - Okay.
有七英里的能見度
Seven miles visibility.
風向270 風速10節
19 winds are at two seven zero at ten knots.
你只有一小時十五分鐘的時間
We show you one plus one five playtime.
兄弟 我可沒看到能從哪進去
Man, I don't see a way in.
我們得橫向切入
We're gonna tip the hat.
橫向切入嗎
Tip the hat?
是啊 你最好抓緊了
Yeah. You might wanna hold on to somethin'.
出發
Here we go.
還能下降十五英尺
Fifteen feet out.
十英尺
Ten feet.
五英尺
Five.
哇 慢點 雷
Whoa, Whoa, easy, Ray.
好了 差不多了
All right. You got it.
好了 開工了 夥計們
All right. Tuck 'em in, boys.
喬比 別用吊籃
Joby, forget the basket.
我們這次得用上雙重固定
We gotta do a double tie-in on this one.
車子要是掉下去了 她也就完了
That car goes, so does she.
門開了
Door's open.
拿上這個
Get this.
繩索固定
Hookin' up.
已經就位了
On the skid.
我們最多只有五分鐘
We got five minutes max.
超過五分鐘會怎樣
What happens in five minutes?
沒什麼 只不過引擎會熄火
It's no big deal. Just engine failure.
好在我只要三分鐘
Good thing I only need three.
- 謝天謝地 - 不 不 納塔莉 別...
- Oh, thank God. - No, no! Natalie, do not...
天哪 天哪 把我救出去
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Get me out of here.
納塔莉 我需要你一動不動地待著
Natalie, I need you to stay perfectly still.
- 我要先穩定住汽車 好嗎 - 快點 求你了
- I have to stabilize the car, okay? - Hurry, please.
車子固定好了
Car secured.
掛住了
Got it.
怎麼回事
What the hell?
該死
Shit.
哇 哇
Whoa, Whoa!
迪倫 天哪 你沒事吧
Dylan! Oh, my God. Are you all right?
天哪 喬比被卡住了
Jesus. Joby's pinned!
啊 該死的
Ah, goddamn it.
喬比 我現在下來
Joby, I'm comin' down.
哈里森 你來駕駛 馬庫斯 給我裝上安全繩
Harrison, you're flyin'. Marcus, rig me a rope.
- 移交駕駛權 - 收到
- Handin' over. - Roger.
已接手
Takin' over.
- 隨時切斷繩子 - 收到
- Be ready to cut. - Roger that.
鉤上了
Hooked up.
出艙門
Out the door.
我準備好了
Ray's clear.
納塔莉 別擔心 我會把你救出...
Natalie, don't you worry. I'm gonna get you outta...
啊
Aaah!
直升機撐不住了
This thing isn't gonna hold!
雷 紅色警報 我們要墜機了
Ray, we are in the red! We are going to crash!
納塔莉 我們現在就出去
Natalie, we are going now!
我抓住你了
I got you.
切繩子 喬比 快甩開
Cut it! Joby, swing!
太好了
Yeah!
我們現在送你回家怎麼樣
What do we say we get you home now.
我覺得這主意實在不錯
I think that's a really good idea.
加州理工學院 加利福尼亞 帕薩迪納市
發生在日本的僊台地震被認為是
Now the sendai quake in Japan was considered to be
1900年以來最強的五大地震之一
one of the five strongest since 1900.
威力巨大 事實上
It was so powerful, in fact,
它將日本的本土移動了八英尺
that it moved the main island of Japan eight feet.
這僅僅是每年發生在全球範圍內
This is just one of the 1.3 million earthquakes
130萬起地震中的一次而已
that occur around the globe each year.
北美最大的一次地震發生於1964年
The largest ever recorded here in North America:
在阿拉斯加州的安克雷奇 有9.1級
Anchorage, Alaska, 1964. A 9.1.
地震持續了有五分鐘
The earth shook for five straight minutes.
釋放出的能量
The energy release
相當於一千萬等量的原子彈
was the equivalent of ten million atom bombs
等同於在日本廣島投下的原子彈
the size of the one dropped on Hiroshima.
但那不是史上記載最強的一次地震
And that's not the biggest earthquake ever recorded.
最強的一次是在四年前
No, the biggest was four years earlier
發生在智利南部的瓦爾迪維亞
off the coast of Valdivia in Southern Chile.
達到了9.5里氏震級
A 9.5 on the Richter scale.
就是那
Right there.
砰
Bam.
這次地震持續了十一分鐘
This quake lasted eleven minutes and spawned a Tsunami
引起了82英尺的海嘯 並將八千英里外的
eighty-two feet high that leveled hilo, Hawaii,
夏威夷西部夷為平地
eight thousand Miles away.
那可是八千英里之外啊
Eight thousand Miles away.
所以 嗯 正是因為地震有著
So, um, It's... It's mass destruction like this
如此之大的破壞性
that shows just how important
才顯示出我們的研究和工作有多重要
the research that we're doing here is,
因為我們要能夠預測地震
because we need to be able to predict these things.
對嗎 可以提前應對
Right? To plan and prepare for them.
- 這位女士 - 教授 您認為
- Yes, ma'am. - Professor, do you think
那樣的事情會發生在這媔
something that intense could happen here?
額 聖安第斯斷層
Well, the San Andreas fault
經過加利福尼亞附近
runs right up the spine of California.
兩個構造板塊的分界線
It's the demarcation line
近些年不斷的在移動著
between two tectonic plates that are constantly moving.
再加上大約150年才會發生一次
Well, and add to that the fact that It's supposed to happen
較為嚴重的地震
every one hundred and fifty years
而我們已經安穩一百多年
and we're about a hundred years overdue.
我想說 這不是會不會發生的問題
I'd say It's not a matter of If.
而是何時會發生
It's a matter of when.
該死的 哥斯拉
Damn, Godzilla.
這次你們又對直升機做了什麼
What the hell did you do to her this time?
和轎車玩了個小小的拔河比賽而已
Played a little tug of war with a car.
你要多久能把它修好
How soon before you get her fixed?
我今天會給馬丁內斯打電話的
I'll call Martinez today.
乾脆給你換件新的算了
Get a new one sent over to maintenance.
埃爾金 別走太快 小心你的屁股
Elgin, you move any faster, you're gonna break that hip.
哈里森說你要和佈雷克一起休息幾天
Harrison said you're taking off with Blake for a few days.
對 明天就走
Yeah. Leavin' tomorrow.
開車送她回去上學
Driving her back up to school.
週末排球隊第一場比賽就開始了
Volleyball team has their first game this weekend,
所以我想我們可以在海岸上玩一圈 露個營
so I figured we'd cruise up the coast. Do a little campin'.
夥計 我真不敢相信她已經上大學了
Dude, I can't believe she's in college already.
我懂 時光飛逝 兄弟
I know. Too fast, brother.
- 我等會來找你 - 好的 夥計
- I'll catch you inside. - All right, man.
勞倫斯 你快看看這個
Lawrence, I gotta show you something.
什麼 啊 小事情
Yeah? Aha. Easy. Easy.
我們剛剛發現了一個罕見的低級地震群
Now, we got a rare low-level seismic swarm
在內華達州的法爾科
out in Falco, Nevada.
24小時之內發生了23次小地震
Twenty-three small quakes, all tiny.
都很小 震級在2.0級到2.6級
2.0 to 2.6 in the last twenty-four hours.
好吧 內華達州的法爾科在哪啊
Okay. Where the hell is Falco, Nevada?
維加斯東南大約35英里
Thirty-five Miles southeast of Vegas,
或許離胡佛水壩五英里
maybe five Miles from the hoover dam.
好吧
Right.
那堥S有斷層啊
There aren't any faults out there.
不包括未知的啊
Any known faults.
如果我們現在過去 而那些迷你的地震還在持續的話
Now, If we get there while the mini quakes continue,
就可以測試我們的理論了
we can test our theory.
如果在地震前磁脈衝率上升的話
And If the magnetic pulse rate goes up before the quakes...
那麼我們可以提前預測
Then we're predicting them.
我們可以提前預測
Then we are predicting them.
好了 讓我們一探究竟吧
All right. Let's go check it out.
- 嗨 爸爸 - 嘿 親愛的
- Hi, dad. - Hey, sweetie.
我在想還有沒有地方放我的自行車
I was wondering If there was room for my bike.
我想我可以騎自行車去上課
I thought that I could ride it to class
這樣我就不用花錢買停車證了
and then I wouldn't have to buy a parking pass.
好主意啊
That's a great idea.
我敢肯定我可以找到方法搞定的
I'm sure I could figure out a way to fit it in.
好的 很好
All right, great.
嗯 我在媽媽這塈鉹ㄗ噾_匙
Um, I can't find the key to the lock at mom's,
可能是我落在化妝台左上角的抽屜堣F
so It's either in the top left drawer of my dresser
也可能在我衣櫃上面的粉紅鞋盒
or on top of the wardrobe in my pink shoe box.
好的 沒問題 我會找到的
Okay, no problem. I'll find it.
今天有計劃了嗎
Don't know If you have plans tonight,
我想帶你去吃晚餐
but I would love to take you to dinner.
你也可以把媽媽帶著一起
You could even invite your mom along.
- 會很有趣的 - 噢 謝了 老爸
- Could be fun. - Oh, thanks, dad.
但我們已經計劃和丹尼爾一起
But we already have plans with Daniel.
爸爸
Dad?
- 你還好嗎 - 當然 我沒事
- Are you okay? - Yeah, of course I am.
我好著呢 沒問題
Totally cool. No problem at all.
好的 那我們明天見吧
Okay. I'll see you tomorrow, then.
好的
Okay.
噢 別忘了我的自行車鑰匙
Oh, and don't forget the bike key.
不會忘的 放心
I won't. I got it.
再見 爸爸 愛你
Bye, dad. I love you.
我也愛你 寶貝
Okay. I love you, too, honey.
再見
Bye.
離婚協議書
快過來 小傢伙們 我們照張相
Come here, you guys. Let's take a picture.
胡佛水壩 克拉克郡 內華達州
勞倫斯 真是不可思議
Lawrence, It's incredible.
這是自我們來這之後第三次迷你地震了
This is the third mini quake since we've been here.
磁脈衝率上升的速度
And the magnetic pulse rate has increased
比之前都快
before each one of them.
我們找到規律了 朋友
We got a pattern, my friend.
是2.0級 我們真的預測到了
That was a 2.0. Our model's predictive.
哦 我們做到了 朋友 終於做到了
Oh! We got it right, man! Finally!
沒錯 我們成功了
Yep, we sure did.
噢 該死的
Oh, shit.
怎麼了
What's wrong?
脈衝率又一次飆升了 這次很強烈
Pulse rates are spikin' again. They're huge.
你開玩笑嗎
Are you serious?
基姆
Kim?
我們要遇到大地震了
We're about to have a major quake.
震級跳到7.1級了
It jumped to a 7.1!
我的天 基姆
Jesus, Kim!
快點離開那兒
Get the hell outta there!
所有人都快從大壩下去 快走 快
Everybody get off the dam! Move! Now! Now!
所有人都快點走 快點
Everybody off! Hurry up!
快到安全障礙後面來
Stay behind the barriers!
快點 快點 到安全障礙後面來
Come on! Come on! Come on! Stay behind the barriers!
基姆 快啊
Kim! Hurry!
快過來 我帶你走
Come here. I got ya.
噢 我的天 快點 我的天
Oh, my God! Please! Oh, my God!
基姆 快跑啊
Kim! Hurry up!
勞倫斯
Lawrence!
基姆
Kim!
別 別動
No! No!
把眼睛閉起來吧
Close your eyes.
你沒事吧
Are you okay?
洛根首長 內華達州大地震 緊急集合
內華達州南部今天發生強烈地震
The Southern part of Nevada was rocked today
地震專家稱之為
by what seismologists are calling
本地區發生過的最為強烈的一次地震
the most destructive earthquake ever reported in that area.
官方報道稱胡佛水壩已被完全摧毀
Officials are saying that hoover dam is a total loss.
哈瓦蘇湖城 尼德爾斯 布萊斯和勞克林
Lake Havasu city, needles, blythe and Laughlin
也遭受了重大損失
also suffered major damage.
來自洛杉磯的救援
Additional support from Los Angeles
包括洛杉磯消防隊的空中救援
including LAFD air rescue,
將會在24小時內抵達現場
is expected to begin arriving in the next 24 hours.
- 報道稱 損失總量為 - 嗨 爸爸
- Reports that the total loss... - Hi, dad.
嘿 親愛的
Hey, honey.
我們剛剛看到新聞了
We just saw the news.
我知道 我很抱歉
I know. I'm so sorry.
我們明天就要出發了
We're headin' out tomorrow.
沒關係 我知道的 這次太嚴重了 爸爸
No, I get it. This one's really bad, dad.
是啊 太可怕了
Yeah, this one's tough.
在地震期間 地震的強度
Earthquakes can rise and fall in intensity
會隨著持續時間而有所增減
during their duration depending on the way...
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
- 很高興見到你 - 我也是
- Good to see you. - You, too.
你好 丹尼爾
Ah, Daniel.
- 雷 很開心終於見著你了 - 我也是
- Ray，good to finally meet you. - It's good to meet you, too.
這房子真不錯啊
Heck of a place you got here, man.
- 啊 謝謝 - 不客氣
- Ah, thank you. - Welcome.
那麼 嗯 爸爸明天就要出發去內華達州了
So, um... dad is heading to Nevada tomorrow.
發生這樣的事情真是可怕
Oh, It's terrible what happened.
在那兒要注意安全 好嗎
Please be safe over there, okay?
好的 我們會的 還有 寶貝 我保證我會補償你的
Yeah, we will. And I promise I'm gonna make it up to you, honey.
爸爸 真的沒關係的
Dad, It's really no problem.
我開車沒那麼糟的
The drive is not that bad.
等等 為什麼不讓我帶你過去呢
Wait. Why don't I take you up there.
我要飛舊金山參加個會儀
I'm flying up to San Francisco for a meeting.
然後我們可以一起去西雅圖
We can head up to Seattle right after.
還能給我個看你那排球賽的機會
It'll give me an opportunity to catch a volleyball game.
好主意
That's a good idea.
還可以讓你媽媽整理她的東西
And it'll give your mom a chance
省的我在礙手礙腳的
to get all her stuff moved in without me in the way.
好吧
Right.
你們要搬進來了嗎
You guys movin' in?
是啊 我 我是想過要告訴你
Yeah. I-I was meaning to tell you,
但我們都沒有機會
but we haven't had a chance to...
祝喜你們了
Congratulations.
謝謝你
Thank you.
謝謝
Thanks.
太好了
That's great.
整片社區都被沖毀了
Entire communities washed away.
到那兒以後打給我
Call me when you get there.
- 我會的 - 好的
- I will. - All right.
爸爸 我愛你 你一定要小心
I love you, dad. You be careful, please.
我會的 我會的 我也愛你
I will, I will. I love you, too.
當地政府提醒 可能還會
Local authorities caution that there could still be...
我去給她拿自行車
I'll get her bike.
很抱歉你們不能一起走
I'm sorry you guys can't go up there together.
我也感覺很糟糕
Yep. Me, too.
雷 雷
Ray. Ray.
我是想告訴你的
I was gonna tell you.
我們也是剛剛做的決定
We just decided to do it.
別多想了
Don't worry about it.
嘿 如果你想
Hey, If you want them...
我也會簽好離婚協議給你的
I'll get those papers signed for you, too.
當時是週日下午
Um, it was a Sunday afternoon.
大家很顯然都沒有上班
Um, obviously, people weren't at work.
也沒有睡覺
They weren't as... asleep.
即便如此 我們知道這次的破壞程度相當
Even so, we know the devastation was fairly...
太糟了
This is bad.
是啊
Yeah.
我們什麼時候出發
What time we headin' out?
下午兩點半 弟兄們都在準備救援裝備
Fourteen-thirty. Guys are preppin' the gear now.
好了 開始工作吧
All right. Let's get to work.
這次的救援行動困難重重
It's a fairly sophisticated rescue operation underway.
這個叫丹尼爾的送佈雷克過去
So this Daniel guy's taking Blake now?
我要是你的話就請病假了
I woulda just called in sick.
所以說我是頭兒 你不是
Uh, It's why I'm the boss and you're not.
就算沒有你的話 我們自己也能撐幾天的
Oh, pretty sure we can manage a few days without ya.
鞋帶鬆了
Shoe's untied.
哈哈哈
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
你在逗我嗎
Are you kidding me?!
佈雷克
Blake.
我想讓你知道
I want you to know that I respect
我尊重你和你爸爸的感情
what you and your dad have.
我也知道你一下子很難
And I know that your mom moving in
接受我和你媽媽住在一起
has to feel like a pretty big step.
但我從未想過破壞你和你父親的關係
But I'm never gonna try to change
或者取代他的位置
what you have with him or take his place.
好嗎
Okay?
好的
Yeah.
很好 當然
Okay, cool.
嘿  你為什麼一直沒有孩子呢
Hey, how come you never had kids?
我有啊
Oh, I did.
這是其中一個
This is one of them right here.
她是舊金山空中一道
She's a pretty nice addition
- 亮麗的風景線 你不覺得嗎 - 天門
- to the San Francisco skyline, don't you think? - "The gate."
- 很順口 對吧 - 是啊 我很喜歡
- Catchy, right? Yeah, I like it.
媽媽跟我說過
Mom was telling me about this.
她說這是城中最高的建築物 對嗎
She said It's the tallest building in the city, right?
完工後不僅是最高的
When It's finished, it'll be the tallest,
也是最結實的 而且已經賣出了百分之八十
strongest and It's already eighty percent sold.
但說實話 我一直忙著蓋樓
But, honestly, I guess I never had any kids
這也許就是我一直沒有孩子的原因
'cause I was always so busy raising these.
奧克蘭市立機場
媽媽發短信來了 她說她今天要和你妹妹一起吃午飯
Mom texted. She's having lunch with your sister today.
是啊 她只在城塈b幾天
Yeah, she's only in town for a few days
真的很想見你媽媽
and really wanted to meet her.
不過我有點緊張
I'm a little nervous though.
蘇珊對我保護欲有點過強了
Susan can be kind of overprotective.
謝謝
Thank you.
喬納森
Jonathan.
早上好 堶}克先生
Good morning, Mr. Riddick.
早上好 你一個人能行嗎 佈雷克
Morning. Gonna be okay, Blake?
行的 我沒事
Yeah, I'll be fine.
你好
Hi.
Hello.
我很抱歉 勞倫斯 我能幫什麼忙嗎
I'm sorry, Lawrence. Can I get you anything?
不用 我沒事 阿列克謝 謝謝你
No. I'm fine, Alexi. Thank you.
你確定你想留在這媔
Are you sure you want to be here?
這樣可以轉移我的注意力
I can use the distraction, actually.
什麼事
Yeah?
外面來了個記者
There's a reporter outside.
她說自己在做一個關於內華達地震的報道
Says she's doing a segment on what happened in Nevada.
哦
Oh.
那我現在就去告訴她 改天再說
I'm gonna tell her that It's not a good time.
不 等等
No, wait a minute.
基姆為此付出了生命
Kim gave his life for this.
人們需要知道
People need to know
我們現在可以預測這些事
that we can predict these things now.
震動
地震學的新進展
勞倫斯·海耶斯教授
基姆帕克博士
想要一本嗎
You want a copy?
我有差不多一千本庫存
I got about a thousand in storage.
地震之前 大概沒有人會相信我們的話
No one listens to us until the ground shakes, I guess.
他們把你同事的遭遇告訴我了
You know, they told me what happened to your colleague.
我們不必現在就進行採訪
We don't have to do this now.
不 就現在
Yeah, we do.
我們準備好了
We're good to go.
- 好的 - 好的
- Okay. - 'Kay.
開始
Rolling.
第一個問題 為什麼
First question. How come
沒有人預測出內華達州的災難
no one saw what happened in Nevada coming?
因為我們不知道那埵麻_層線
Because we didn't know there were any fault lines out there.
為什麼不知道
Why not?
與主流觀點相悖
Contrary to popular belief,
科學家並非無所不知
scientists don't know everything.
我瞭解到 你曾經公開表示過 有一天
I understand that you publicly stated that, someday,
科學家們 將有能力準確的預測到地震
scientists will be able to predict earthquakes.
事實上 到昨天為止
Well, actually as of yesterday,
我們一直都相信我們可以做出預測
we now believe that we can predict them.
教授
Professor!
能跟你談談嗎
Talk to you a sec?
好的 很抱歉 失陪一下
Yeah. I'm sorry. Excuse me.
怎麼了
What is it?
這是我們監測站的磁脈衝率
Current pulse rates at our monitoring stations.
都沿著聖安德烈亞斯的斷層線
All along the San Andreas fault.
平均數值從82增長至85
Their averages are spiking from eighty-two to eighty-five,
峰谷差位於舊金山
with the biggest jumps coming from San Francisco.
比我們在內華達州地震觀測到的
More than twenty points higher
要高出20個點
than what we saw in Nevada.
不不不 這不可能
No. No, no, no. There's no way.
我們查了兩遍
We checked. We double-checked.
我們重置了所有儀器
Then we reset all the instruments
查了第三遍 結果一樣
and triple-checked. Those are the counts.
等一下
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
等等
Wait a minute.
呃
Um...
好的 呃
Okay, uh...
如果 呃
If, uh...
如果我們畫一條線 從聖安德烈亞斯底部
If we draw a line from the bottom of the San Andreas
直通到胡佛大壩
up to the hoover dam,
可以發現這條線幾乎是沿著科羅拉多河的
it almost literally follows the Colorado river,
而那條河流是自然變形造成的
which is a natural deformation event.
從地理角度看 變形通常發生在大陸板塊邊緣
And geologically, deformation events mark boundaries.
它們能標記出界限
They mark boundaries.
所以 要是
So, what If...?
要是這一大片土地
What if this whole chunk of land
都與地殼板塊相連呢
is connected to our tectonic plate?
那就表示 昨天在內華達州發生的地震
That would tell us that what happened yesterday in Nevada
並非異象
was not an anomaly.
不 如果這是板塊運動的開始
No, what if it was a precursor movement
而板塊的邊界
along the leading edge of the plate boundary fault
從洛杉磯一直延續到舊金山
from Los Angeles all the way up to San Francisco?
你是說
Are you saying you think
整個聖安德烈亞斯斷層可能崩塌
the whole San Andreas fault might go off?
沒錯 我說的就是這個意思
Yes, that's exactly what I'm saying.
我們該通知誰
Who should we call?
通知所有人
Everybody.
哦 真見鬼
Mmm. Oh, bloody hell.
哦 我有紙巾 給你
Oh! I have something. Here.
- 我真是個十足的傻瓜 - 不會啦
- I'm a complete idiot. - No.
非常感謝你 你真好
Thank you very much. It's very kind.
沒關係 順便說一句 我叫佈雷克
Yeah, no problem. Um, I'm Blake, by the way.
好的 我 我叫佈雷克
Oh, yeah. I'm-I'm Blake.
我不是佈雷克 我是本
I'm not Blake! I'm Ben.
我叫本 泰勒 很高興見到你
Ben Taylor is my name. Pleased to meet you.
很高興見到你
It's nice to meet you.
剛剛跟你一起來的是你父親嗎
So was that your father you came in with?
丹尼爾 堶}克
Daniel Riddick?
他是我媽媽的男友
Um, he's my mom's boyfriend.
啊
Ah.
你要和他見面嗎
Are you meeting with him?
哦 不 我 呃 我還差得遠呢
Oh, no. I... uh... not even close.
只是想想罷了 我是來應聘的
I wish. I'm interviewing for a job here
堶}克先生是我未來老闆的
and Mr. Riddick is the boss of the boss
老闆的老闆
of the boss that I'd be working for.
那你是來應聘什麼工作的
So, um, what kind of job are you interviewing for?
工程或者設計方面的工作
Anything in engineering or design.
我不挑剔 也不自滿
I'm not picky or proud.
我只是 我只是想在這堣u作
I just... I just want to work here.
如果你是一個建築師 這是 呃 這是最理想的地方
If you're an architect, this is the, uh, place to be.
你好 我叫奧利
Hi. I'm Ollie.
他是我哥哥
He's my brother.
你好 很高興見到你 奧利
Hi. It's nice to meet you, Ollie.
我是佈雷克
I'm Blake.
你知道嗎 你很漂亮
You know, you're quite beautiful.
謝謝誇獎
Why, thank you.
奧利 你 抱歉
Ollie. Do you...? Sorry.
你記得 你記得我們討論過的事嗎
Do you remember... do you remember what we discussed?
安靜地坐好 什麼也別說
Sit still and no talking.
很少有人會帶弟弟來
It's not normal to bring little brothers
參加面試
to job interviews.
別讓我難堪 好嗎
And let's not embarrass me, okay?
我可以幫他要你的電話號碼嗎
Do you mind if I get your phone number for him?
奧利 這真是 你在說什麼啊
Ollie! It's exactly... what?!
你肯定不敢問的 接著我就得聽你
You'll never ask for it. And then I'll have to listen
沒完沒了的說 你有多後悔
to how much you regretted not getting it.
泰勒先生
Mr. Taylor?
卡特女士現在可以見你了
Ms. Carter will see you now.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我 呃
I, uh...
祝你好運
Uh... Good luck.
謝謝
Thank you.
你坐在這兒
And you, sit here.
不許再亂說話了
And don't say another word.
- 你好 - 我是本
- Hello. - I'm Ben.
我們要馬上過去
We're gonna head straight over.
太好了
Excellent.
你想聊點什麼
What do you want to talk about?
你是從哪堥茠
Um, where you from?
英國
England.
本覺得
Ben thought that while our parents
趁著爸媽在海上旅行
were going to be on a cruise,
我們應該在他面試結束以後
he and I should take a holiday here in the city,
- 在城堛悸 - 很好
- after his interview. - Awesome.
哦 你想聽聽看我們的日程安排嗎
Oh. Would you like to hear our itinerary?
洛杉磯
蘇珊
Susan.
很高興終於能和你見面了
It's nice to finally meet you.
我也是
You as well.
既然丹尼爾已經讓你搬去和他一起住了
Now that Daniel's asked you to move in with him,
你們應該都是認真的
things must be pretty serious.
是的
Yes.
你們好 我是拉娷
Hi. I'm Larissa.
今天由我來為你們服務
I'll be taking care of you today.
我可以介紹一下今天的特色菜嗎
Can I tell you about our specials?
好的 我很願意聽你
Please, I'd love to hear what you're...
抱歉 你能過會兒再來嗎 拉娷
Actually, could you come back in a few minutes, Larissa?
好的 沒問題
Yeah. Sure.
我聽說你之前結過婚
So I understand you've been married before?
呃 是的
Uh, yes.
- 你只有一個女兒 對嗎 - 是的
- And you have just the one daughter. Right? - Right.
另一個女兒在事故中淹死了
Your other one drowned in an accident?
是的 你說話很直接
Yes, to put it bluntly.
哦 我不是故意的 我
Oh, I didn't mean it like that. I...
呃 你能等我一下嗎
Um, can you just give me one minute?
喂 一切都還好嗎？
Hi. Everything okay?
嗯 呃
Yeah, uh...
我正在去維修站的路上 馬上就要出發救援了 呃
Oh, I'm on my way to maintenance before we head out, and, uh...
我打擾你了嗎
Am I interrupting anything?
不是什麼重要的事 怎麼了
Nothing important. What's going on?
我只是 我想跟你說聲對不起
Look, I just... I wanted to tell you I was sorry
我昨天不應該這麼對你
for how I acted yesterday.
真的沒關係 雷
No, Ray, really.
不 艾瑪 呃 我只是沒法突然接受
No, Emma, um, I just wasn't ready to hear
你和佈雷克搬去和別人一起住
about you and Blake moving in with someone else.
我 我應該提前告訴你的
I... I should've told you before.
佈雷克怎麼想
Hey, how's Blake feel about it?
你知道 她還是想讓我們一家子團聚的
You know, she'd like us to be a family again.
我 我 我覺得她應該很難
I... I... I think It's gonna be hard for her to...
艾瑪
Emma.
- 天啊 - 艾瑪
- Oh, my God. - Emma.
這埵a震了
We're having an earthquake.
天啊 雷
Oh, Jesus, Ray.
呃 我得離開這
Uh-uh, I gotta get outta here.
你在哪
Where are you?
呃 泰特韋斯頓
Um... uh, the Tate weston.
該死 你在頂樓 艾瑪 聽著
Shit. You're on the top floor. Emma, listen,
把大家叫去樓頂 能叫多少叫多少
get as many people as you can and get to the roof.
我開直升機過來接你 知道了嗎
I'm in the helo and I'll get you from there, okay?
知道了
Okay, okay!
好的 去樓頂等我 寶貝
Okay. Get to the roof, honey.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no. No!
到桌子底下去
Under the table.
蹲下 找掩護 堅持住
Drop, cover and hold on!
勞倫斯 堣饈髒きq6.5躍至8.5
Lawrence, the Richter just jumped from 6.5 to an 8.5.
什麼意思
Well, what does that mean?
威力十足
Powers of ten!
是之前的一百倍
So It's a hundred times stronger now!
別擔心
Don't worry.
現在加州理工學院應該是最安全的地方
Caltech is probably the safest place to be right now.
教授 看起來整個聖安德烈亞斯的斷層線
Professor! It looks like the whole San Andreas fault line
都被激活了
is being activated.
一路向舊金山進發
And It's heading towards San Francisco.
好了 結束了
All right. All done.
好的
Okay.
很高興認識你 奧利
Well, it was really nice to meet you, Ollie.
祝你在這堛控o愉快
I hope you have fun while you're here.
再見 佈雷克 我也很高興認識你
Bye, Blake. It was nice meeting you, as well.
再見
Goodbye.
哦 我差點忘了
Oh, and, um I almost forgot.
你介意我借一下你的書嗎
Do you mind If I borrow your book for a second?
告訴本 我會幫他說好話的
Tell Ben that I'll put in a good word for him.
- 再見 - 再見
- Bye. - Bye.
我真想趕快到二十歲
I can't wait to be twenty.
代客泊車
- 請上車 - 謝謝
- Here you go. - Thank you.
地震了
It's an earthquake!
快走 帶我們離開這
Well, go, go, go! Get us outta here!
哦 天啊
Oh, God.
走 快走
Go! Hurry, hurry!
好的 快點
Yes! Go, go, go!
我的天啊
Jesus Christ!
見鬼 快走
Oh, shit! Go!
我的腿
My legs!
- 你沒事吧 - 天啊
- You okay? - Oh, my God.
他 他死了 他
He's... he's dead! He...
- 佈雷克 佈雷克 佈雷克 - 他死了
- Blake? Blake? Blake. - He's dead.
你還好嗎 受傷了嗎
Are you okay? Are you hurt?
沒 沒有 我應該沒受傷
N... no... no, I don't think... I don't think so.
但我的腿被卡住了
But my legs are stuck.
快點
Come on.
好 好
Okay. Okay.
我會把你帶出去的 好嗎?
We're gonna get you outta here. Okay?
噢 天啊 好吧
Oh, God. Okay.
快想 快想想
Think. Think.
丹尼爾?
Daniel?
佈雷克 我去找人幫忙
Blake, I'm gonna go for help.
- 不 丹尼爾 - 我很快回來
- No, Daniel... - I'll be right back.
- 我很快回來 - 不 丹尼爾 別
- I'll be right back. - No, Daniel. Don't.
別丟下我一個人
Please don't leave me alone!
丹尼爾! 不 丹尼爾
Daniel! No, Daniel.
趕快撤離!
Keep moving!
快 快點! 我們走 救命!
Come on. Hurry! Let's go! Help!
救命啊! 快走!
Help! Keep moving!
快走! 我們走! 救命!
Keep moving! Let's go! Help!
有個女孩困在車堣F!
There's a girl trapped in a town car!
- 在哪? - 停車場
- Where? - In the parking garage!
來幫幫忙吧 噢 天啊
You gotta come help. Oh, God!
起來! 起來!
Get up! Get up!
快離開大樓 到外面去!
Out of the building! Get outside!
堶}克先生! 堶}克先生?
Mr. Riddick! Mr. Riddick?
堶}克先生!
Mr. Riddick!
救我!
Help me!
快! 快!
Come on! Come on!
快跑
Move it.
佈雷克
Blake.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
蘇珊! 艾瑪!
Susan! Emma!
蘇珊! 我們去屋頂!
Susan! We gotta get to the roof!
離開這兒!
We've gotta get out of here!
不! 這邊
No! This way!
別擋路!
Get out of my way!
蘇珊! 蘇珊!
Susan! Susan!
噢 天啊! 啊!
Oh, God! Aaah!
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
這邊! 出口在這!
This way! Get over here!
- 女士 我們快跑! - 好 好
- Ma'am, we got to go! - Okay. Okay.
快走 快走!
Keep moving! Keep moving!
拉娷!
Larissa!
拉娷 跟我走!
Larissa, you have to come with me!
我們得到樓頂上去
We've gotta get to the roof!
各位!
Everybody!
救 救援直升機馬上就到
There-there's a rescue helicopter coming!
等等 要往上走!
Wait! We've gotta go up!
噢 天哪 天哪
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
雷 你要快點來
Ray, you better be right about this.
雷
Ray.
哇
Whoa!
噢
Oh!
噢 天哪
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Uh...
去那邊!
Up there!
噢 該死
Oh, shit.
快點 艾瑪 快 我們沒時間了
Come on, Emma. Come on. We gotta go.
艾瑪 快跑!
Emma, run!
艾瑪
Emma.
雷!
Ray!
艾瑪!
Emma!
我抓住你了!
I got you!
噢 雷
Oh, Ray.
艾瑪 有沒有受傷?
Emma, are you hurt?
嗯...
Um...
- 你受傷了嗎? - 我想沒有
- Are you hurt? - I don't think so.
好 會沒事的 但是聽好
Okay. It's gonna be okay, but listen.
我們必須離開這
We gotta get outta here.
你到前排左邊位置坐好
I need you to get to the front left seat.
- 我馬上來 好嗎? - 好的
- I'll be right there. Okay? - Okay.
該死!
Shit!
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
噢 天哪
Oh, God.
- 雷! - 抓緊了!
- Ray! - Hold on!
救命! 來人救救我!
Help! Somebody help me!
救命! 有人嗎!
Help! Somebody help!
- 我是雷 - 爸爸 快救我!
- This is Ray. - Dad, please help!
佈雷克 怎麼了?
Blake, what's wrong?
一場強震!
In a huge earthquake!
丹尼爾不知道哪去了
I don't know where Daniel went.
我被困在車庫的轎車
I'm stuck in a limo in a garage.
爸爸! 我真的好害怕
I'm really, really scared, dad!
你受傷了嗎 寶貝?
Baby, are you hurt?
沒有...
No...
佈雷克! 該死
Blake! Goddamn it.
怎麼了? 什麼情況?
What? What is it?
該死 她手機信號中斷了
Shit. Her cell service just went out.
救援人員不會那麼快
There's no way rescue personnel are gonna be
趕到車庫去救她
diggin' in garages any time soon.
還有很多人員聚集在地面上等待救援
Too many populated places above ground.
那... 呃... 我們該怎麼辦?
What, uh... What are we gonna do?
去救我們女兒
We're going to get our daughter.
佈雷克! 佈雷克!
Blake! Blake!
救命 我在這!
H-help! I'm over here!
佈雷克! 佈雷克 我是本 你沒事吧?
Blake! Blake, It's Ben. Are you okay?
我出不去 樓頂在塌陷
I can't get out. The roof's collapsing.
我的腿被卡住了
My legs are trapped.
好 好
O-okay. Okay.
奧利 我們把石塊撬開
Oh, Ollie, we need to lift this beam
讓她的腿可以活動
to get the pressure off her legs.
- 好嗎? - 好的
- Okay? - Yeah.
試試這個
Oh, let's try this.
好 準備好沒有?
Okay, ready? Ready?
一 二 三
One, two, three.
加油 奧利
Come on, Ollie.
用盡全力
Give it everything you've got.
我在使勁!
I am!
起作用了!
It's working!
奧利!
Ollie!
本? 奧利?
Ben? Ollie?
我們在 我們在呢
We're still here. We're still here.
噢不 不
Oh, no. No.
你們快逃出去吧
You guys have to get out of here.
這堸角W就要塌了
This building's gonna collapse.
不
No.
不可能
There's not a chance in hell
我們絕不會把你丟下的
we're leaving you in there.
好了 好了
Okay. Okay.
好了 用這個
All right. Here we go.
太棒了 起作用了!
Brilliant. It's working!
撐到最高了
It won't go any higher.
我還是出不來!
I'm still stuck!
啊!
Ah!
奧利! 她動了!
Ollie! She's moving!
快 快 快
Hurry, hurry. Hurry!
你沒事吧?
Are you okay?
- 沒事 - 你確定?
- Yeah. - Are you sure?
是的
Yeah.
謝謝 謝謝你們
Thank you. Thank you, guys.
樂意效勞
Pleasure.
幹得漂亮
Good job.
快走 餘震又來了
Come on. It's another aftershock.
- 我們快離開這 - 好的
- We've got to get out of here. Okay!
小心! 快點 快!
Look out! Hurry! Come on!
快離開這
We have to get away from these buildings.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
佈雷克! 這邊 走這邊!
Blake! This way! This way!
上帝啊 我的天!
Jesus! Oh, my God!
奧利! 佈雷克!
Ollie! Blake!
快! 走 走!
Come on! Go! Go!
真想不到丹尼爾會扔下我不管
I cannot believe that Daniel just took off.
真是個混蛋
What an asshole.
請路上的人讓開 讓開
Step aside, people.
我得盡快聯繫我父母
I gotta get ahold of my parents.
讓他們知道我沒事
I gotta let them know I'm okay.
電話打不通 我試過了
Cellphones aren't working. I've tried.
我們得找一家電器商店
We need to find an electronics store.
你們的書上有購物指南嗎?
Does that book of yours list businesses?
我的書堣偵繷ㄕ
My book has everything.
好消息是 我們大部分的應急系統
The good news is most of our emergency systems
還在運作 在這
are still working. Here.
我們從17個監控器中檢測到了信號
We've got signals coming in from seventeen monitors.
我們剛剛經歷了一場9.1級強震
We just experienced a 9.1.
勞倫斯... 來看看這個
Lawrence... You need to see this.
獲取到什麼了?
What do we got?
這是震前採集的波頻率數據
Here are the pulse rates before the quake.
好的
Yeah, okay.
這是目前的波頻率
And here are the pulse rates now.
相同
The same.
甚至更高
Or higher.
所以地震並沒有減弱
So the earthquake didn't diminish them.
噢 天哪
Oh, man.
噢 情況不妙
Oh, this is not good.
阿列克謝 把所有還在斷層上運作的監測站數據
Alexi, I want all the data from every monitoring station
現在全部匯報給我
still up along the fault line and get it for me now.
- 好的 - 出什麼事了?
- Right. - What's going on?
該死
Shit.
噢 天 都摔壞掉了
Oh, man. This thing's fried.
快點 我需要所有人的幫忙
Come on. I need everybody.
- 我們要做什麼? - 讓你來廣播
- W-what are we doing? - Gettin' you on the air.
我們要通知所有人
We need to warn people.
要怎麼做? 信號都中斷了
How? There's no way to upload a signal.
這堨i是加州理工學院
You're at Caltech.
好了 你們誰想在獨立研究課上得A?
Okay, who wants an A in independent study?
我開一門新課:
I'm startin' a new class:
"如何通過入侵電視台來拯救人類"
"How to save lives by hacking media outlets."
哦不錯 我參加
Hell yeah, man. I'm in.
很好 帶上筆記本電腦 出發
Sweet, bro. Get your laptop. Let's go.
在這邊 快快快
Right here. Move, move, move.
好了 起
Here we go. Up. Lift.
應該不遠了
It should be just up ahead.
就在那兒
There it is.
好 任何需要靠電運作的東西都不能用
Okay, anything running on electricity isn't gonna work,
所以我們要找一個撥盤的或者按鍵的電話
so we have to find a rotary or a push button phone.
你怎麼知道這些的?
How do you know all this?
我爸爸教我的 他在洛杉磯消防局工作
My dad. He works for L.A. fire and rescue.
在這呢
Over here.
太好了 我找找通訊線
Great. I'll look for a landline.
找到了!
I got one!
爸爸
Dad.
爸爸 我出來了 我沒事
Dad. I got out. I'm okay.
她沒事
She's okay.
讓我和她說說話
Oh. Let me talk to her.
佈雷克?
Blake?
媽媽?
Mom?
噢 感謝上帝 親愛的
Oh, thank God, honey.
丹尼爾還好嗎?
Is Daniel okay?
他丟下我跑了 媽媽
He left me, mom.
他怎麼了?
He what?
他告訴保安我的位置
He told a security guard where I was
然後就丟下我不管了
and then he just took off
有一對兄弟聽到了談話
and these two brothers that I met overheard him
就趕過來救了我
and they came to help me.
我現在和他們在一起
I'm with them right now.
他把她丟下了
He left her?!
我們這就過去接你 親愛的 你在哪?
We're comin' to get you, honey. Where are you?
我在唐人街的一家電器店
I'm in an-an electronics store in Chinatown.
親愛的 會沒事的
Honey, It's gonna be okay
但是你聽我說
but I need you to listen to me.
快出去
Getting outta there
那邊馬上就會堵得死死的
is gonna be a complete gridlock nightmare,
到高地上去 那塈韟w全
so get to higher ground. It's safer.
- 也方便我能看見你 - 好的
- That's where I'm gonna be able to see you. - Okay.
還記得週末我們給馬洛媢L生日的地方嗎?
Do you remember where we spent Mallory's birthday weekend?
科伊特塔?
At Coit tower?
是的 就是山上那座
Yeah. That-that tall
- 高高的水泥噴嘴一樣的建築 - 沒錯
- cement nozzle thing on the hill. - Exactly.
別停下 直接過去
Don't stop anywhere. Go there.
我們在那見
That's where We'll meet.
堅強 寶貝 我們這就來接你
Stay strong, honey. We're comin' to get you.
好的 等下 媽媽
Okay. Wait, mom. Mom.
你和爸爸怎麼在一起?
How-how are you and dad together?
以後再解釋 好嗎寶貝?
We'll explain later. Okay, honey?
我愛你
I love you.
我也愛你們 再見
I love you guys. Bye.
你好 我是丹尼爾
Hi, you've reached Daniel.
有事請留言 我會盡快回復
Please leave me a message and I'll get back to you.
你竟敢把我女兒扔下不管了?
You left my daughter?
如果你沒死 我會過去親手宰了你
If you're not already dead, I'm gonna fuckin' kill you.
幹得好
Thatta girl.
好了 我們得離開這
All right, we need to get going.
那你爸爸怎麼來接我們?
So how is your dad going to pick us up?
他駕駛直升機 正趕過來
He's on his way in a helicopter.
真是太酷了
That's so cool.
我需要你們幫我在地圖上找到科伊特塔
I need you to look up Coit tower on your map.
輪到你打電話了
It's your turn.
你們的父母一定很擔心
Your parents will be worried sick.
謝謝你
Thank you.
待在路面上
Stay on the street.
我們去哪兒?
Where are we going?
別擋路!
Get out of my way!
嘿! 那是我的地盤!
Hey! That was my spot!
你知道嗎 你和佈雷克通話的時候
You know, when you were talking to Blake
那是馬洛堥咫F之後
that was the first time I heard you say Mallory's name
我第一次聽你提到馬洛堛漲W字
since we lost her.
你記得我們在舊金山旅遊的時候的照片嗎?
Hey, do you know that Blake keeps pictures
佈雷克一直留著
from our San Francisco trip?
記得 在她的回憶盒
Yeah, in her memory box.
真想不到 我們有一天還會回到那堨h
It's ironic. Us heading back up there.
那一次很開心的旅行
It was a fun trip.
我們在哪?
Where are we?
貝克斯菲爾德 已經是一片廢墟了
Bakersfield. Or what's left of it.
離舊金山大概還有90分鐘的航程
We're just about ninety minutes from San Francisco.
雷?!
Ray?!
你關掉引擎了嗎?
Did you just turn off the engine?
是的 我們的變速裝置出故障了
Yeah, we got a gearbox failure.
肯定是剛才在洛杉磯撞到的
Must've been that hit we took in L.A.
現在只能自行降落了
I'm gonna have to auto rotate down.
自什麼?
A-auto-what?
撞到地上
We're gonna crash.
- 好 好吧 - 抓緊了
- Right. Okay. - Hold on.
開始了
Here we go.
抓緊!
Hold on!
我的天啊!
Oh, my God!
要到了 要到了
Almost there. Almost there.
就在那堶偶
Just gonna set it down right here.
我們身上都是燃料 快點從這堨X去
We got fuel all over us. We need to get outta here.
快點 離開
Come on. We gotta go.
- 低下身子 - 好的
- Stay low. Stay low. - Okay.
沒事的 我們繼續走
It's okay. We just gotta keep movin'.
繼續往前 好
Just gotta keep movin'. All right.
給我!
Give it to me!
不! 這是我的!
No! It's mine!
快 快 快
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
進去 進去
Get in, get in, get in, get in.
這車好像是偷來的
Looks like It's been stolen.
好 我們再偷一次
All right. Well, We'll steal it again.
雷
Ray.
冷靜點
Easy.
我需要那輛卡車
I'll be needin' that truck.
今天可不行
Not today.
哦 天吶
Oh, my God.
這次地震
The quake centered
以洛杉磯市中心東部二十英里處為中心
about twenty Miles east of downtown Los Angeles.
信號塔都毀了
Cell towers are down.
城堛漱j部分電力也中斷了
Most of the city's electricity, down.
通訊處於停滯狀態
Communication at a virtual standstill.
對加利福尼亞南部地區
The devastation to Southern California
造成了災難性的破壞
is expected to be massive.
事實上 整個州都受到影響
In fact, the entire state will take a hit.
- 我們已經收到有關建築物塌陷的報道 - 我們進去了
- We're already getting reports of collapsed buildings - We're in.
- 北至舊金山和海灣地區 - 太棒了
- As far north as San Francisco and the surrounding bay area. - Yes.
至少已經發生過五次餘震了
There have been at least five aftershocks.
好的 我們開始了
Okay. Here we go.
製片人告訴我們
Uh, producers are telling us
我們有來自洛杉磯的首次現場直播
we have our first live feed from Los Angeles.
拍攝開始 五 四...
We're rolling. Five, four...
塞雷娜·約翰遜現在正在
Serena Johnson is on the ground
加利福尼亞工學院地震學中心現場
at the seismology center at caltech.
你好 克奡
Hello, Chris.
現在坐在我身邊的是
I'm here with Dr. Lawrence Hayes,
加利福尼亞工學院地震研究室執行理事勞倫斯·海耶斯教授
executive director for earthquake studies at caltech.
他和他的研究夥伴基姆帕克博士
He and his research partner, Dr. Kim park,
設計出了一個可以預測地震的理論模型
have come up with a model that predicts earthquakes.
他們預測到洛杉磯會發生地震
They knew L.A. was going to get hit.
可是沒有人理會他們
But nobody listened to them.
現在讓我們一起來聽聽吧 請說吧 教授
It's time now to listen. Go ahead, doctor.
好的 用地震學術語來說
Okay. Um, in seismology terms,
我們現在所經歷的叫做地震群體事件
what we're experiencing is what we call a swarm event.
基本上來說 加利福尼亞
Um, basically, California's
整個地殼構造板塊都移動了
entire tectonic plate has shifted.
目前看來 我們在洛杉磯
Yes, it seems the quake we experienced here
發生的地震 一路蔓延
in Los Angeles did major damage
對舊金山造成了極大的破壞
all the way up in San Francisco.
是的 不過他們感受到的地震
Yeah. Yeah, but the earthquake that they felt
來自中央谷
was from movement along the fault line
斷層線的活動
in the central valley.
而尾部的斷層線還沒有開始移動
Their end of the fault line has not moved yet.
更重要的是 大家必須知道
Uh, more importantly, people need to know
地震尚未結束
that the shaking is not over.
我說的地震 而不是餘震
And It's not aftershocks I'm talking about.
舊金山還會再次發生地震
San Francisco will get hit again.
而且會比這次的更加嚴重
And It's going to be a bigger monster this time.
我們的樣機預測震級至少是9.5
Our models are predicting a 9.5 or greater.
震動會極為強烈 即便是在加利福尼亞
It will be so big that even though It's happening
發生的地震
here in California
你在東海岸也會有震感
you will feel it on the east coast.
所以 我在這堶n鄭重的提醒
Now, I cannot emphasize this enough
舊金山的人們
to the people of San Francisco:
你們得馬上離開 就現在
You need to get out. And I mean now.
如若來不及的話 你們需要
And, If you can't, you need to find
找到任何何以掩護或者抓牢的東西
any means possible to drop cover and hold on.
因為你們能不能活下來全靠它了
Because your life is gonna depend on it.
願上帝與你們同在
God be with you.
餘震依舊
Aftershocks continue
搖晃著洛杉磯地區
to rock the Los Angeles area...
你有沒有想過 要是沒有失去馬洛堛爾
You ever think about what our life would be like.
我們的生活會是什麼樣
If we hadn't lost mallory?
專家們建議大家...
People are advised to...
艾瑪 別這樣
Em, don't.
我想過 每時每刻都在想
I do. All the time.
我們已經向前看了
We've moved on.
不 我們沒有
No, we didn't move on.
我們停在了那個時刻
We stopped moving.
她又不是因為你沒有看好而死去的
You didn't lose her on your watch.
確實 但是我失去她了
No. But I lost her.
我們能不討論這個嗎
Can we not talk about this?
你欠我的
You owe it to me.
又是這樣
This!
自從她死了你幾乎每天都是這樣
This is the most I've gotten out of you since she died.
我真的想知道 雷
I need to know, Ray.
是因為我嗎 是我做了什麼嗎
Was... was it me? What did I do?
因為我從沒怪過你
Because I never blamed you.
我不想談這個
I don't wanna talk about it.
我 這還有什麼關係呢 她都不在了
I... it doesn't matter. She's gone.
現在你也離開了
Now you're gone.
還有什麼意義呢
What's the point?
我覺得問題在於
I guess the point is
這就是我沒留下的原因
this is why I didn't stick around.
聽起來是極其嚴重的情況 勞麗
Sounds like a terrible situation there, Laurie.
我知道當時一定很艱難...
I know that it must have been very difficult...
嗨 注意 小心
Hey! Look out! Watch out!
嗨 嗨 快停下
Hey! Hey! You have to stop!
雷
Ray!
這是什麼情況
What is this?
聖安德烈亞斯斷層
The San Andreas fault.
我說過我們該走另一條路的
I told you we should've gone the other way.
因為你預測到了會發生這個嗎
Because you knew this was gonna happen?
哦
Oh.
你
You!
我們真的非常感激你們
We owe you guys a huge thanks.
不必了
No need.
我們差點也犯了同樣的錯
We nearly made the same mistake ourselves
不過我們駛離道路的時候爆了個車軸
but busted an axle when we ran off the road.
多虧我視力比他的好
Thank goodness my eyes are better'n his.
請問這埵雩纀鉰飪L去嗎
Do you know If there's any way around this?
這個嘛 198號公路可能還行
Well, uh... the one-ninety-eight might not be out.
- 剛好能繞過去 - 有多遠呢
- Through the pass. - How far is that?
你們得掉個頭走 大概七十英里
Oh, ya gotta backtrack, maybe, seventy Miles or so.
先生 冒昧問一句
Sir, If you don't mind me Askin'...
你的帽子是哪來的
Where'd you get your hat?
你們可真幫了我們大忙了
You guys really bailed us out.
真的不用我們送你們去哪嗎
You sure we can't fly you anywhere?
不用了 我們兒子住在山上
Yeah. Our son lives in the mountains.
那堨i沒地方能降落
There's no place to land.
多謝你的車了
Thanks for the wheels. You bet.
路上小心 拜
Be safe. Bye.
再過幾分鐘油就加滿了
We should be fueled up in a couple of minutes.
好啊 太好了
Okay, great.
你還好吧
Everything okay?
你剛才問我是不是因為你
You asked me before If it was you.
其實不是
It wasn't.
我知道你不怪我
I knew you didn't blame me.
我...我只是不知道該怎麼面對馬洛堛漲
I... I just didn't know how to deal with Mallory's death.
那天帶馬洛堨h漂流是我的主意
It was my idea to take mallory rafting that day.
雷
Ray.
你不該這樣責怪自己
You can't blame yourself for what happened.
可當出事的是自己的孩子時感覺真的太難過了
It's just different when It's your own kid.
我知道
I know.
- 爸爸 - 馬洛
- Dad! - Mallory!
有時候 我無法把她當時看我的表情從腦海奡坏h
Sometimes I can't get that look she had outta my head.
就是那一刻
The moment she realized
她意識到我救不了她
that... I wasn't gonna be able to save her.
然後每天回家面對你和佈雷克
And then coming home every day to you and Blake
只會使之變得更難
only made it harder.
因為我們再也回不到從前了
Because nothin' was the way it used to be.
而我們的從前...
And the way it used to be was...
是那麼完美
It was perfect.
我本該對你敞開心扉的
I should've let you in.
我只是不知道該怎麼做
I just didn't know how.
而我們之間卻這樣結束了 我很抱歉 艾瑪
I'm so sorry for how things ended with us, em.
我真的很抱歉
I really am.
若是連你都救不了我們的女兒...
If you couldn't save our daughter...
其他人更不行
Then nobody could have.
我真的很想她
I miss her so much.
我也是
Me, too.
去救我們的女兒吧
Let's go get our daughter.
快走啊 繼續走
Let's go! Keep it movin'!
快走 加油 快走
Let's go! Come on. Let's go.
順著疏散路線走
Follow the evacuation route.
再走幾條街就到倫巴第街道
Just a few more blocks to Lombard Avenue,
然後就能直接到科伊特塔
which leads to Coit tower.
我能問問
Do you mind If I ask
你為什麼戴著兩條一樣的項鏈嗎
why you wear two of the same necklaces?
呃...
Um...
其中一條是我妹妹的
One of them used to be my sister's.
我... 自從她去世後我就開始把它戴上了
I, uh... I started wearing it after she died.
在那場事故發生的前一年
We had given them to each other
這是我們送給彼此的聖誕禮物
for Christmas the year before.
我... 我很抱歉 我... 我不是有意...
I'm... I'm so sorry. I... I didn't mean...
沒關係的 我並沒打算掩飾什麼
No. It's okay. I'm... I'm not hiding them.
嗨 快看吶
Hey. Check it out.
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?
他們應該有個電源箱的
They should have a supply box.
堶惘釦畯怚帢o上的東西
It'll have stuff that we can use.
是這個嗎
Is this it?
沒錯
Yes!
好 看著
Oh, okay. There we go.
每個城市都有一個現場急救員
Every city has a tactical channel
用來通話用的火災指揮用頻道
that first responders use to communicate on.
我們可以留著聽最新動態
We can listen in and we can see what's going on.
好 拿著這些
Okay. Here. Take these.
好的
Yeah.
拿著這個
Take this.
- Mre是什麼 - 就是應急食品
- What's an mre? - Meals ready-to-eat.
這些東西有三年以上的保質期
These things have a shelf life of over three years.
嘗起來不怎麼樣
Wow. They don't taste so good.
酷
Cool.
佈雷克
Blake!
我覺得我們可能去不了
I think we're going to have a problem
你說的那個噴嘴樣的地方了
with that big nozzle thing you were talking about.
什麼 你在說什麼
What? What do you mean?
我的天吶
Oh, my God.
我們得啟用B計劃
We have to go to plan B.
我們好像沒有B計劃吧
I didn't think we had one.
現在有了
We do now.
我們得去另外一個最高的地方
We need to get to the next highest ground
給我爸爸發信號
so that we can signal my dad
所以我們要去諾布山
in the helicopter. That would be Nob Hill.
那是市堻怜牧漲a方
It's the highest point in the city.
在另一邊
It's the other way.
走吧
Okay. Come on!
佈雷克 等一下 等一下
Bl-no. Blake, wait! Wait! Just... just wait.
借過 讓一讓 讓一讓
Coming through. Move, move, move.
佈雷克 只有我們在往那個方向去
Blake, we'd be the only ones going that way.
我爸爸說去最高的地方
My dad said to get to higher ground,
那我們就去最高的地方
so that's what we gotta do.
可... 要是他來不了怎麼辦
But... what If he doesn't make it?
我知道這聽起來可能有點瘋狂
Listen, I know that this sounds crazy.
不過你得相信他一定會來的
But you have to trust me that he will.
我... 我...
I... I c...
本
Ben.
你知道按鍵式電話能和
Did you know about the push-button phone
陸線連接起來用嗎
working with the landline?
電源箱
The supply box?
火災指揮用頻道
Tactical radio channels?
我真覺得我們應該和她一起
I really think we should stick with her.
好吧 看來我們是要去諾布山了
Okay. Looks like we're going to Nob Hill.
好的 走吧
Okay. Let's go.
這條信息是加利福尼亞
The following message is transmitted at the request
應急管理部門要求發送的
of the California emergency management.
請居民們立刻撤離
Residents are encouraged to evacuate immediately.
看來整個城市都在撤離
Looks like the whole city's evacuating.
艾瑪 機場好像去不了了
Em, we got a problem at the airport.
那我們能從哪堶偶
Where are we gonna land?
沒辦法了
We can't.
至少不能在城市堶
At least, not in the city.
跟我來
Come with me.
哦... 好的
Uh... okay.
你不是開玩笑的吧
You gotta be kidding me.
艾瑪 我們現在沒地方降落了
Em, we have no place to set this plane down
我們必須盡可能的靠近科伊特塔
and we have to get as close to Coit tower as we possibly can.
三分鐘內 我們就會飛到內河碼頭上方
In three minutes, we're gonna be over the embarcadero.
然後呢
And?
然後我們跳到At&t運動場堨h
And, we're gonna drop into AT&T park.
可我不會跳傘
But I don't know how to parachute.
沒關係 我們雙人串聯跳傘
That's okay. We're gonna tandem-jump.
我 我我覺得還是待在飛機堣騆好
I-I-I think we should just stay with the plane.
飛機一旦耗盡燃油
The plane's gonna nosedive in the pacific
就會直接俯衝掉到太平洋
as soon as it runs out of gas.
那好吧
Okay. Mm.
相信我
Trust me.
我的天
Oh, my God!
準備好了嗎
You ready?
- 我像準備好的樣子嗎 - 那是
- Do I sound ready?! - Yep!
我有好久沒沒讓你上二壘了
It's been a while since I got you to second base.
隨著勞倫斯·海耶斯博士的沉重警告
With a grave warning from Dr. Lawrence Hayes
在電視廣播上播出
blanketing the airwaves...
舊金山已開始實施撤退方案
San Francisco has begun evacuation procedures.
海岸巡邏隊希望任何一個有船隻的人士
The coast guard is asking anyone with access to a boat
都能參與其中...
to will please volunteer in the process...
斷層線的活動
fault line in the central valley.
而斷層線的尾部還沒有開始移動
Their end of the fault line has not moved yet.
舊金山還會再次發生地震
San Francisco is going to get hit again,
而且會比這次的更加嚴重
and this will be a much bigger monster.
我真希望所有人都聽到了我們的預警
I hope we've given everyone enough warning.
這真是破天荒頭一次
Would be the first of its kind.
這就是你說的嗎
This is it, isn't it?
此時此刻 我希望我是錯的
Right now, I wanna be so wrong.
大家快找掩體
Everyone, take cover!
這很快就會結束的
This will be over soon here.
為舊金山的人們祈禱吧
But pray for the people of San Francisco.
你知道嗎 nob是個俚語
Did you know "nob" is a slang term
意思是富裕 富有
which means "rich" or "wealthy".
是"Nobility"貴族的簡寫
"It's a shortened version of the word 'nobility',
因為住在這堛熙ㄛO富有家庭
because of the families that live there.
這堣S被稱為斯諾希爾
It is also derisively known as 'snob hill'."
怎麼了
what is it?
丹尼爾造的那座建築
Daniel built that building.
我的天吶
Oh, my God.
我操
Oh, shit.
快走 快走
Move! Move!
走啊 奧利
Come on, Ollie!
奧利
Ollie!
我想回家
I want to go home now!
堅持住
Just hold on!
一會就好 我保證
It's gonna be okay. I promise!
他們在那媟|喪命的
They're gonna get killed out there.
艾瑪 到體育場的邊上去
Em, get to the side of the stadium.
我馬上就回來 我馬上就回來
I'll be right there. I'll be right there!
這堣ㄕw全 到體育場的邊上去
It's not safe here. Get to the side of the stadium!
馬上到體育場的邊上去
Go to the side of the stadium right now!
這座樓要塌了 快走啊
This building's gonna collapse. You need to move!
趕快 趕緊離開街道
Hurry! You gotta get off the street!
到體育場的邊上去 快啊
Get to the side of the stadium! Right now!
體育場的邊上去 到體育場的邊上去
Side of the stadium. Get to the side of the stadium!
快點 快點 快離開街道
Come on. Come on. Come on. Off the street!
去體育場 到體育場的邊上去
Get to the stadium. Side of the stadium!
快點 離開街道
Come on! Get out of the street!
沒事的 有我在
It's all right! I got you.
有我在 起
I got you. And up!
- 這邊 雷 - 帶上她
- Over here, Ray! - Take her.
- 帶上她 艾瑪 - 好的
- Here. Take her, em. - I got her!
你會沒事的 你會沒事的
You're gonna be okay. You're gonna be okay.
會沒事的
It's all right.
大家都蹲下
Everybody down!
大家都好吧 有沒有人受傷
Everybody okay? Anybody hurt?
沒有
No.
艾瑪 你沒事吧
Emma. You okay?
沒事
Yeah.
你是怎麼知道這埵w全的
How'd you know we'd be safe?
因為我們躲在一個堅固的東西邊上
Just get up against something sturdy.
想要保護好自己
Protect yourself.
就要尋找地震活命三角區
Triangle of life.
地震活命三角區是由加拿大人道格-庫普提出的一種理論，
是指地震發生後，室內的人應該躲在大而堅實的物體旁，
這樣牆體和梁倒下後能與該物體形成一個三角空間，
躲在這個空間堛漱H便可活命
走吧
Let's go.
她會平安無事的
She's gonna be okay.
但我們要怎樣才能橫穿過去呢
But how do we get through that?
我們不橫穿過去 我們繞過去
We don't. We go around it.
嗷
Oh.
好了
Oh, okay.
我們得把這個碎片取出來
We have to get that out of there.
如果繼續帶著它前進的話 傷勢會加重的
If you try walking with it, it could cause more damage.
這會很疼的 你準備好了嗎
This is gonna hurt. Are you ready?
啊 啊
Gah! Ahh.
本
Ben!
沒事兒 我沒事兒
I'm all right. I'm all right.
你覺得你還能繼續前進嗎
Do you think you could put some weight on it?
我們得接著走 我們還得爬過那座山
We have to keep moving. We gotta get up that hill.
行
Yeah.
好的 來吧
Okay. Here.
這次地震究竟有多強烈
How bad did they get hit?
九點六級
9.6.
有史以來最強烈的一次地震
Largest quake in recorded history.
噢 不
Oh, no.
這兒已經燒了一陣子了
Coit's been burning a while.
她肯定逃到別的地方去了
She's gone someplace else.
寶貝 你在哪兒呢 在哪兒呢
Now, where are you, baby? Where are you?
你的B計劃是什麼
What's your plan b?
噢 該死的
Oh, shit.
怎麼了
What's happening?
我們得趕緊走
We gotta go.
海水的波動表明海嘯即將來襲
Water being pulled out like that's a Tsunami.
我們得離開這個港灣 趕快
We gotta get outta the bay, now.
等等 等等 等一下
Wait. Wait, wait a second,
- 讓我歇一下 - 讓你休息一下吧
- just give me one second. - Give you a second.
天啦
God!
氣象部門剛對加州中部和北部的沿海地區
The weather service has issued a Tsunami warning
發佈了海嘯預警
for coastal areas of northern and central California,
包括馬林郡 納帕
including the following Marin, napa,
舊金山 蒙特媯市陞
San Francisco and Monterey.
快 我們得趕快走
Come on, guys. We gotta go!
快走 我們得趕快走
We gotta go! We gotta move fast!
我們得去丹尼爾那座寫字樓
We gotta get to Daniel's building.
雷
Ray.
我看到了
I see it!
好吧 抓緊了
All right, hold on!
我們得在它達到浪峰之前穿過去
We gotta get over it before it crests!
快啊 快啊
Come on! Come on!
我們可以的 我們能行的
We're gonna make it. We're gonna make it!
噢 他媽的
Oh, shit!
雷
Ray!
見鬼了
Shit.
這是什麼動靜
What's that noise?
我們的位置還是不夠高
We're not high enough.
趴...趴下 趴下 快躲起來
Get... get down! Get down! Take cover!
抓緊了 奧利
Hold on tight, Ollie!
啊 啊
Ah! Ah!
噢 啊
Uh! Aah!
本
Ben!
奧利
Ollie.
水勢還在上漲
The water's still rising.
我們還得往上走
We have to get higher.
這邊
This way!
本
Ben.
奧利 來 抓緊了
Ollie, come. Grab on.
噢 我的天啦
Oh, my God.
她會在哪兒呢 雷
Where is she, Ray?
她是個聰敏的孩子
She's a smart girl.
她肯定會找個高處躲起來
She'd know to head for one of these high-rises.
嗯
Hm.
我們一定得找到她
We just gotta find her.
你還好吧
Are you all right?
讓我們來檢查一下你腿上的傷勢
We need to take a look at that leg.
奧利 看能找到點什麼東西
Okay. Ollie, see If there's something
我們可以用來做繃帶
that we can use as a bandage.
再看看能不能找到點乾淨的水
And see If you can find clean water.
好的
Yeah.
好拉
Okay.
好拉 讓我們看看情況怎麼樣
Okay. Let's see what we're dealing with here.
怎麼了
What?
你實在太...太不可思議了
You're absolutely... Unbelievable.
老媽肯定會喜歡她的
Mum's going to love her.
我找到幾條毛巾
There are a few towels in here.
噢 太好了
Oh, great.
我再去找點水
I'll look for some water.
跳過來 快
Just jump! Come on!
我接住你了
I got you.
布賴恩特大街
嘿 我看到有人駕著船
Hey! I can see some people in a boat!
不會吧 不會吧
No way. No way!
那是我父母
Those are my parents!
媽媽 爸爸
Mom! Dad!
- 媽媽 - 救命啊
- Mom! - Help!
爸爸 嘿
Dad! Hey!
爸爸 媽媽
Dad! Mom!
媽媽
Mom!
他們聽不到我們
They can't hear us.
怎麼了
What?
艾瑪 如果再找不到她
Em, If we don't get to her soon,
我們就快要沒油了
we're gonna need some gas.
我們還有大概一個小時 最多一個半小時的油量
We got maybe an hour, hour and a half tops before we...
- 雷 - 怎麼啦
- Ray. - Yeah?
先停一下
H-hold on.
噢 天啦 噢 我的上帝啊 那是佈雷克
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, It's Blake!
- 噢 我的天啦 - 艾瑪
- Oh, my God! - Emma!
我們終於找到她了
We found her.
佈雷克
Blake!
奧利
Ollie!
奧利 奧利
Ollie! Ollie!
奧利
Ollie!
我抓住你了 我抓住你了
I've got you! I've got you!
佈雷克在哪兒
Where's Blake?
她在後面
She's back there!
待在這兒別動 奧利
Stay here, Ollie.
佈雷克
Blake!
Blake! Bla...
不 不 不
no! No! No!
這棟樓在下沉 我們得趕緊走
The building's sinking! We have to move.
我們得往上走
We have to move up.
快走 奧利 快
Come on, Ollie, hurry!
噢 不 不 不 我的天啦 佈雷克
No, no, no, no. Oh, my God, Blake!
艾瑪 你來駕駛這艘船
Em, take the wheel.
我看到了一個入口 我去找她
I see a way in. I'm going after her.
雷
Ray!
我會把她帶回來的
I'm bringin' her back.
我保證
I promise.
佈雷克
Blake!
爸爸
Dad!
- 不要害怕 - 那個門被鎖住了
- Don't worry. - The door's blocked!
佈雷克 不要害怕 我會把你救出去的
Blake, don't worry. I'm gonna get you outta here.
好嗎 我會救你出來的
Okay? I'm gettin' you out!
爸爸 我好害怕
Daddy, I'm scared.
我快要窒息了
I'm running out of air!
爸爸 我覺得我不行了
Daddy, I don't think I can do this.
佈雷克 堅持住 堅持住
Blake, you hold on, hold on!
這邊
There!
本 我不希望佈雷剋死
Ben, I don't want Blake to die.
她不會死的
She's not going to die.
我這就回去救她 好嘛
I'm going back for her. Okay?
但我要你好好地待在這兒
But I need you to stay here.
好嘛
Okay?
乖
Good boy.
奧利
Ollie!
本
Ben!
奧利 到我背上來 到我背上來
On my back! On my back, Ollie!
佈雷克會死的
Blake's going to die.
是不是
Isn't she?
爸爸
Dad.
沒事兒的
All right.
爸爸
Dad.
我愛你 爸爸
I love you, dad.
請 請轉告...
And please, please tell...
請轉告媽媽 我也愛她
Please tell mom that I love her, too.
佈雷克 不要放棄
Blake, don't you quit on me!
爸爸 我很抱歉 爸爸
Daddy. I'm sorry, dad.
佈雷克
Blake!
不要啊
No!
佈雷克
Blake!
佈雷克 佈雷克
Blake! Blake!
讓開 奧利 讓開
Move, Ollie. Move-move.
加油 呼吸 佈雷克
Come on. Breathe, Blake.
呼吸 親愛的
Breathe, honey.
我們得離開這兒 去砸開一扇窗戶
We gotta get outta here. Break a window!
噢 天啦
Oh, my God.
讓開 走遠點兒
Move! Get outta the way!
小心
Watch out!
上來 快上來 快
Get on! Let's go! Let's go!
快走 快走 奧利 快上去
Move. Move, Ollie, move.
- 快來 雷 - 接住她 艾瑪
- Come on, ray. - Take her, Emma.
我接住了 好了
I got her. It's okay.
好了
Here you go.
醒醒 親愛的 醒醒啊
Wake up, honey. Come on.
讓我來 我們得離開這兒 艾瑪
Get her. Get us outta here, Em!
這棟樓要塌了
Okay. The building's coming down.
都趴下
Everybody down!
好了 佈雷克
Okay, Blake.
爸爸和我 我們都在這兒
Okay, dad and I, we're right here now.
我們都在這兒
We're right here.
呼吸呀 佈雷克 呼吸呀
Breathe, Blake. Breathe.
加油
Come on.
不要離開我 呼吸 加油
Don't leave me. Breathe. Come on.
爸爸和我都在這兒 好嘛
Dad and I are right here, all right?
雷
Ray...
我的孩子呀
My baby.
我不能再失去你了
I'm not gonna lose you, too.
絕不
No.
加油
Come on.
噢 噢 我的上帝啊
Oh. Oh, my God.
好啦 好啦
Okay. Okay.
媽媽
Mom.
我在這兒 我就在這兒
I'm right here. I'm right here.
嗯
Yeah.
沒事兒了 沒事兒了 沒事兒了
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
現在我們可以更加清晰地看到
We are now getting a better picture
地震造成的毀壞場景
of the scale of the devastation.
而在很多街區我們都可以看到
And this was the sight in many neighborhoods:
親朋好友相擁在一起
Families and friends huddled together,
雖然心有餘悸 但依舊慶幸自己的劫後餘生
shaken but grateful to still be alive.
地質學家將會密切關注
Seismologists will be keeping a close watch
全球地殼板塊的活動情況
on all of the world's tectonic plates
因為聖安德烈亞斯這場地震
as the San Andreas quake
可能會波及全球
could have rippling effects throughout the globe.
讓我們再來關注一下國內的情況
Closer to home, nerves are finally calming
對於只是略有震感的東海岸
on the east coast where the shaking was felt hey.
緊張的情緒終於得到平復
Across the entire eastern seaboard.
- 你做得非常好 - 政府的官員正在考慮建立一套...
- You did good. - Officials in Washington want to establish a new...
謝謝
Thank you.
這是大家的功勞
We all did.
白宮
And the white house.
以及舊金山政府
Authorities in San Francisco are attributing
對那位專家致以衷心的感謝
a tremendous amount of lives saved thanks to local experts,
正是因為他及時向大眾發出地震預警從而拯救了無數人的生命
who were able to give ample warning of the massive quake.
同時 灣區的災後重建工作也已經開始
Meanwhile, recovery efforts have begun in the bay area
聯邦緊急事務管理局 國民衛隊和聯合國救援組織
where Fema, the national guard and U.N. Relief teams
都已經趕赴災區
have all been mobilized.
成千上萬的志願者
Aided by the thousands of volunteers
也都紛紛奔赴灣區
pouring into the state.
我們在天上的父 願人人都尊您的名
Our father who art in heaven, hallowed by thy name.
願您的天國降臨
Thy kingdom come...
奧利  本
Ollie. Ben.
我 我在船上找到了這個
I, uh, I found this on the boat.
謝謝
Thank you.
嘿  你們對佈雷克幫助 我深表感激
Hey, I wanna thank you guys for bein' there for Blake.
是啊 多謝你們
Yeah, thank you.
不客氣
You're welcome.
但實際上 她幫我們的更多
But it was more like she was there for us.
至少我這麼覺得
I think.
這真是讓人難以置信
This is incredible.
那 接下來呢
So... what now?
接下來我們重建家園
Now we rebuild.
# 樹葉轉黃 #
All the leaves are brown
# 天空灰藍 #
And the sky is gray
# 我隨處閒逛 #
I've been for a walk
# 在這樣一個冬日 #
On a winter's day
# 我感到安全又溫暖 #
I'd be safe and warm
# 如果這是在洛杉磯 #
If I was in L.A.
# 加州之夢 噢 在這樣一個冬日 #
California dreamin', Oh, on such a winter's day
# 樹葉轉黃 #
All the leaves are brown
# 天空灰藍 #
And the sky is gray
# 我隨處閒逛 #
I've been for a walk
# 在這樣一個冬日 #
On a winter's day
# 我感到安全又溫暖 #
I'd be safe and warm
# 如果這是在洛杉磯 #
If I was in L.A.
# 加州之夢 噢 在這樣一個冬日 #
California dreamin' on such a winter's day
# 停車不入教堂 #
I stopped into a church
# 穿過走廊 #
I passed along the way
# 我雙膝跪下 #
Well, I got down on my knees
# 假裝禱告 #
And I pretended to pray
# 牧師喜歡寒冷 #
You know the preacher likes the cold
# 他知曉我會駐留 #
He knows I'm gonna stay
# 加州之夢 噢 在這樣一個冬日 #
California dreamin', Oh, on such a winter's day
# 我感到安全又溫暖 #
I'd be safe and warm
# 樹葉轉黃 #
All the leaves are brown
# 天空灰藍 #
And the sky is gray
# 我隨處閒逛 #
I've been for a walk
# 在這樣一個冬日 #
On a winter's day
# 如果不是告訴了她 #
If I didn't tell her
# 我今天就會離去 #
I could leave today
# 加州之夢 #
California dreamin'
# 在這樣一個冬日 #
On such a winter's day
# 噢 在這樣一個冬日 #
Oh, on such a winter's day
# 在這樣一個冬日 #
On such a winter's day
# 耶 耶 #
Yeah, yeah